Well, let's see. Let's use Bayes theorem to calculate it.
我们使用贝叶斯定理计算下概率
We'll use the following notation,
我们将使用以下标记
S will stand for sick,
S 表示生病
H will stand for healthy,
H 表示健康
and the plus sign will stand for testing positive.
+ 表示测试结果阳性
So since one out of every 10,000 people are sick,
因为每 10,000 人有 1 人生病
we get that P of S is 0.0001.
因此 P(S) 为 0.0001
Similarly, P of H is 0.9999.
同样 P(H) 为 0.9999
Since the test has 99 percent accuracy,
因为对于患者和健康人士来说
both for sick and for healthy patients,
测试的准确率都为 99%
we see that P of plus,
因此可以看出
given S is 0.99,
P(+|S) = 0.99
the probability that the sick patient will get correctly diagnosed.
即正确诊断生病人士的概率
And that P of plus given H is 0.01,
P(+|H) = 0.01
the probability that the healthy patient will get incorrectly diagnosed as sick.
即健康人士被错误地诊断为生病的概率
So plugging that into the new formula,
将这些值代入新的公式中
we get the probability of being diagnosed as positive when you're sick is exactly 0.0098,
得出生病并且诊断为阳性的概率正好是 0.0098
which is less than 1 percent.
低于 1%
Really? Less than 1 percent?
不可能吧？竟然低于 1%？
When the test has 99 percent accuracy?
测试的准确率高达 99% 呢
That's strange, but I guess that's the answer to the quiz.
很奇怪 但这就是这道练习的答案
So, less than 1 percent falls in this category of 0 to 20 percent.
低于 1% 属于 0% - 20% 类别
I'm still puzzled though, why less than 1 percent If
我还是有点迷惑 如果测试的准确率为 99%
the test is correct 99 percent of the time.
为何会低于 1%？
Well, let's explore. Let's go back to the tree of possibilities.
我们来看看原因 我们回到概率树部分
Let's say we start with 1 million patients,
假设有 100 万人
and they have two options, healthy and sick.
他们要么健康 要么生病
Now, since 1 out of every 10,000 patients is sick,
因为每 10,000 人有 1 人生病
then from this group of 1 million patients,
那么在这 100 万人当中
100 will be sick and the remaining 999,900 will be healthy.
100 人将生病 剩下的 999,900 人将健康
Now let's remember that for every 100 patients,
注意 每 100 人当中
99 get correctly diagnosed and one gets incorrectly diagnosed,
有 99 人诊断正确 1 人诊断错误
this happens both for sick and for healthy patients.
对生病和健康人士来说都一样
So, let's see how many of these patients will get diagnosed positively or negatively.
我们来看看将有多少人诊断结果为阳性或阴性
Out of the 100 sick ones,
在 100 位生病者当中
99 will be correctly diagnosed as
99 人将正确地诊断为阳性
positive and one will be incorrectly diagnosed as negative.
1 人错误地诊断为阴性
Now, out of the healthy ones,
在健康人士当中
1 percent or 9,999 will be incorrectly diagnosed as positive and
1% 或 9,999 人将错误地诊断为阳性
the remaining 99 percent or 989,901 will be correctly diagnosed as negative.
剩下的 99% 或 989,901 人将正确地诊断为阴性
Now let's really examine these four groups.
我们来仔细研究下这四个群组
The first group is the sick people who we will send for more test or treatment.
第一组是将接受更多测试或治疗的生病人士
The second is the unlucky sick people that will be sent home with no treatment.
第二组是将不接受任何治疗直接回家的倒霉生病人士
The third is a slightly confused healthy people who will be sent for more tests.
第三组是接受更多测试的困惑健康人士
And the fourth group or the majority is
第四组是多数人群
the people who are healthy and were correctly diagnosed healthy and sent home.
他们是健康人士 并且正确地诊断为健康者 接到通知直接回家
But now, here's the thing,
现在的问题是
we know we tested positively,
我们知道测试结果是阳性
so we must be among one of these two groups,
因此肯定位于这两组当中
the sick people who tested positively or the healthy people who tested positively.
测试结果阳性的生病人数或测试结果阳性的健康人士
One group is much larger,
其中一组更庞大
it has 9,999 people,
有 9,999 人
whereas the other one has only 99 people.
另一组只有 99 人
The probability that we're in this group is much larger than that we're in this group.
我们在这组的概率比在另一组的概率大很多
As a matter of fact, the probability that we are in the small group is
实际上 属于更小型组的概率是
99 divided by the sum, 99 plus 9,999,
99 除以 99 与 9,999 的和
which is, you guessed it, 0.0098,
结果为 0.0098
which is smaller than 1 percent,
小于 1%
this is the probability of being sick if you are diagnosed as positive.
这是诊断为阳性并且生病的概率
But why is the group of healthy people who tested positively so
但是为何健康人士测试结果阳性的人数比
much larger than the group of sick people who tested positively?
生病人士测试结果阳性的人数要多很多
The reason is because,
原因是
even though the test only fails 1 percent of the time,
虽然测试只有 1% 的错误率
that 1 percent is much,
但是这个 1% 是个很大的数字
much larger than the one out of 10,000 rate of sickness among the population.
比 1/10,000 的生病概率大很多
In other words, in a group of 10,000 healthy people,
换句话说 在 10,000 人的健康人群中
1 percent or a 100 of them will get misdiagnosed as sick.
1% 或 100 人将被错误地诊断为生病人士
On the other hand,
另一方面
in a group of 10,000 people,
在 10,000 人当中
around one will be sick,
有 1 人将是生病人士
this is much less.
这个人数少了很多
So if you know you've tested positively,
如果你的测试结果为阳性
you are still more likely to be among the 100 errors than among the ones sick.
你依然更有可能是 100 位测试错误的人士之一 而不是生病人士之一
And how much more likely?
概率大多少呢？
Around 100 times, and that's why our probability of being
大约 100 倍
sick while being diagnosed positively is around 1 percent.
因此诊断为阳性并且生病的概率大约为 1%
This phenomenon is called the False Positive,
这种现象称之为假阳性
and it has been a nightmare for the medical world,
对于医学 法律等很多领域来说
the legal world and many others.
都是个糟糕的现象
Search False Positives on Google,
Google 一下假阳性
and you'll see many cases in which people have been misdiagnosed, misjudged etc.
就会搜到很多诊断错误或审判错误的案例
So always be aware of false positives,
一定要小心假阳性
they are very sneaky.
它们不容易被发现